thinkmoney.co.uk 2018-02-17

# Privacy policy | thinkmoney

The information contained in this privacy notice tells you how your personal information is collected and used by Think Money Limited and the Think Money Group companies.

Your information will be held by Think Money Limited which is part of the Think Money Group of companies (collectively referred to as ‘we’, ‘us’, ‘our’ or the ‘Group’). The companies within the Group are set out in section 12 of this Privacy Policy.

Your information will be securely held in the Think Money Group systems, and any third party systems where required, to enable us and the companies within the Group that you may have dealings with, either now or in the future, to be able to administer any products or services that they provide to you.

Last update : 21/08/2017

1\. What information we may collect from you

The information we collect from you will depend on the product or service you apply for, or the service that we provide to you. This will likely include the collection of:

  * your personal details (e.g. name, date of birth)
  * address details
  * contact details (e.g. phone number, email)
  * sensitive data* (e.g. medical information)
  * financial information
  * employment information
  * information on how you use our website(s) and products and services

You may not have to provide all the information requested but doing so will help us to ensure we have a fuller understanding about you to allow us to provide services to you.

#### Sensitive Data

*The Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) defines some personal information as “sensitive data” (physical or mental health, sexual life, criminal proceedings or offences, religious beliefs, race or ethnic origin, political opinions or trade union membership). This information may be necessary to collect, for example, when you apply for an insurance quote. Where we need to collect and process sensitive data about you, by providing this information to us you give your explicit consent for us and any other third party to process this sensitive data as set out in this Privacy Policy.

2\. Joint accounts

If you provide personal information about someone else, for example when a joint application is made, you must do so with the consent of the other person. If you enter into a product jointly with another person, your personal data and any information about the product or service provided to you will be shared with the other person.

The personal information about a joint applicant may be used in the ways as described in this privacy policy.

3\. How and where we collect information

We will collect information from you in various ways, including:

  * when you make an application or enquiry within the Group;
  * information received from a third party, for example when we are required to run checks with a third party, such as a credit reference agency or fraud prevention agency, or where you have previously consented for your information to be shared with us;
  * when you provide information to the Group to help them provide and/or administer any product and/or service that is provided to you by the Group;
  * when you participate in market research, competitions and promotions provided by, or on behalf of the Group;
  * when we may need to obtain up to date information about you to meet our legal and regulatory obligations;
  * where you have provided your consent; or
  * where you use a website controlled by the Group.

4\. How we may use your information

The personal information you provide may be used in a number of ways, for example;

  * responding to your requests, enquires or complaints;
  * to provide our product or services and to notify you of any changes or developments with the products, services or platforms we provide;
  * statistical analysis;
  * profiling purposes;
  * helping us and the other Group companies to understand and develop the Group’s respective businesses, including new and innovative products and services;
  * to meet our legal and regulatory obligations and for the prevention of fraud, money laundering and terrorist financing;
  * advising you of promotions, competitions and offers;
  * using information gathered from market research or evaluating the effectiveness of marketing and training;
  * undertaking financial reviews; or
  * where we have your consent.

We will keep your information for as long as we reasonably require it, or where we are required to do so under a legal obligation.

5\. How we may share your information

We may share your personal information with companies or organisations outside of the Group where:

  * we need to do so to provide you with products or services, for example credit reference agencies;
  * we have entered into an arrangement for a third party to provide us with services, for example IT platforms and services, communication services or market research;
  * where we’re required to do so under a legal or regulatory obligation or court order; or
  * where we have your consent to do so.

6\. Safeguarding your personal information

We take the protection of personal data very seriously and we will maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the information you have provided.

7\. Credit Applications

If you submit a credit card, loan or mortgage application, we may share your information with one or more of the lender(s) whose relevant products we offer (either directly or via a credit broker). We may also make one or more credit searches for each applicant when making our recommendation or selecting a lender. The chosen lender may also search your record to verify your credit worthiness and identity. The credit reference agency will add details of any searches to your record which can be seen by other organisations that make searches and they may use it to help make credit decisions about you, to prevent fraud and money laundering and to trace debtors. Where there is a joint application the outcome of any credit search may be shared with both persons who make an application.

This condensed guide explains what we will do and how we, the lender and the credit reference and fraud prevention agencies will use your information. Or if you prefer to read the full version, click here.

8\. Insurance Applications

If you make an enquiry for an insurance quote or purchase an insurance policy online or over the phone your information will be shared with insurance providers or administrators to provide you with a quote and/or to administer and provide the insurance policy. More information about how your information may be used by the insurer and/or administrator can be found in the policy documents you will receive.

9\. Using fraud prevention agencies

The personal information we have collected from you will be shared with fraud prevention agencies who will use it to prevent fraud and money-laundering and to verify your identity. If fraud is detected, you could be refused certain services, finance or employment. Further details of how your information will be used by us and these fraud prevention agencies, and your data protection rights, can be found by contacting us or email us at [contactus@thinkmoney.co.uk](mailto:contactus@thinkmoney.co.uk)

10\. Sharing your information outside of the EEA

Although we do not routinely transfer personal information outside the European Economic Area (EEA), we may be required to transfer your personal data to staff or to one of our suppliers who are based outside of the EEA. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

11\. How we may contact you about products and services we provide to you

To help us keep you up to date about the products and services that we provide to you and to ensure that you’re kept fully informed we may contact you by letter, telephone, email, text message or may send you messages by any online customer platforms. If you don’t want to be contacted in a particular way then you can request this at any time.

It is important that you keep us up to date when you change your contact details to ensure that we use your up to date contact information.

12\. How your information may be used to contact you about products and services

We, Think Money Limited, is part of the Think Money Group of companies (the names of which are set out below) and offer a range of financial products and services to customers. Where we, and other companies within the Group have your consent, you may be sent marketing communications by email, text message, telephone or by social media. You can opt out of any of these communications at any time by contacting us using our contact details set out in this privacy notice, emailing us at [unsubscribe@thinkmoney.co.uk](mailto:unsubscribe@thinkmoney.co.uk) or unsubscribing from the messages you may receive.

The table below provides information on the companies within the Think Money Group and the names they also trade under.

Group Company | Trading name  
---|---  
Intelligent Lending Limited |  Ocean Ocean Finance Ocean Mortgages Your Loan Deals  
Think Money Limited | thinkmoney  
Think Insure Limited |  Think Insure thinkmoney Insurance Ocean Insurance  
Gregory Pennington Limited |  Gregory Pennington Debt Advisory Centre Debt Advisory Centre Scotland Think Link  
Freeman Jones Limited |  Freeman Jones IVA Advice Line  
Wilson Andrews Limited | Wilson Andrews  
All About Money Limited | think2claim  
Ideal Finance Limited | Ideal Finance  
  
13\. Other types of advertising

When you visit our website or similar websites Google may use our advertisements for the purposes of remarketing, and they may appear on other third party websites you visit across the internet for remarketing purposes, including cross-device remarketing. Google and other third parties will use cookies to tailor advertisements for website users based on their previous visit to our website. More information about cookies can be found below.

We do not have any control over the advertisements you see on other third party websites however you can request to opt out or customise these advertisements by using the [Google Ads Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

14\. Recording calls

We may record any telephone calls you make to us or we make to you or any other third party. This is for training, monitoring and quality purposes. Some telephone calls may be observed by staff for training and development purposes.

15\. Obtaining a copy of your personal information

You can request a copy of the information that the Group company holds about you by writing to the address below. Up until 25th May 2018 a fee of £10 may be payable for this information. 

You should contact us if any information we hold about you is incorrect, or you would like your personal information removed from our records. We will then investigate this for you.

Data Protection Officer  
Think Park  
Mosley Road  
Trafford Park  
Manchester  
M17 1FQ 

16\. Updates to this privacy notice

Any updates to this privacy notice will be found on this page. If we make any significant changes to the way we may collect and use your personal information we will notify you of this change.

17\. Cookies

When using this website, some information may be collected automatically using 'cookies'. These are small text files that facilitate the processing of your data and enable us to analyse how the website is being used. Cookies can be temporary or permanent.

Temporary cookies form part of the security process while you are using the website; permanent cookies identify the link you used to find our website, check your browser so that we can make sure that our website and services work well with your computer and to help us monitor traffic on our website.

#### Why are cookies used?

They help visitors. Cookies allow sites to do things like provide personalised content and remember their log-in details and settings. You can turn them off - this won't stop a website from working, but it might mean it won't work as well as it could, or that you have to do the same thing more than once.

They help website owners. Cookies tell website owners things like: what search engine a visitor used to find the website, how often they've visited it, how long they've spent on it, and so on.

We've set out below the cookies that we may use and those that are set by third parties on our website.

Cookie | Name | Purpose | More Information  
---|---|---|---  
Mixpanel | mp_ | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our website. They keep track of when a visitor enters and leaves the website. | Click [here](https://mixpanel.com/optout/) for more information about Mixpanel and how to disable this cookie.  
Hotjar | _hj | These cookies are used to record anonymous videos about how visitors use our website. They keep track of how visitors engage with pages on our website. | Click [here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out) ffor more information about Hotjar and how to disable this cookie.  
Google Analytics | _utma _utmb   
_utmc _utmz | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our website. They keep track of when a visitor enters and leaves the website and any search engines and keywords that are used, including any personal and/or sensitive data. | Click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) for more information about Google Analytics and how to disable this cookie.  
Session Variables | ASP.NET_SessionId ASPESSIONID | These cookies are used to keep all information about the visitor’s session of the website and are essential for the website to work. These expire when the browser is closed. |    
Session Variables | VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE | This tracks a layout version that the YouTube applet will use when displayed on the website. |    
DoubleClick Cookies | test_cookie ID | These are 3rd party cookies served by DoubleClick. They serve adverts to visitors based on the websites they’ve been to previously. | Click [here](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx) for more information about DoubleClick and how to disable this cookie.  
Our Cookies | sitetrack | This is used to see if a user has visited our website for the first time. |    
Our Cookies | sitetrack2 | This is used to see if a person returns to our website. This cookie is only created if sitetrack is present. |    
Our Cookies | PCC Landing | This is used to find the route a user entered our website through. |    
Our Cookies | AppID | This tracks if a user revisits our website. |    
Our Cookies | isLoggedIn | This is used to track website journey behaviour. |    
  
Except for essential cookies, all cookies will expire after 10 years.

#### Disabling/Enabling Cookies

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings on your browser and by clicking on the disable button below. Please remember though that disabling certain cookies may affect the functionality of our website.

None of the features of our website will be affected - giving you the full experience.

#### Disable

If you are using Microsoft Windows Explorer:

  * Open 'Windows Explorer'
  * Click on the 'Search' button on the tool bar
  * Type 'cookie' into the search box for 'Folders and Files'
  * Select 'My computer' in the 'Look In' box
  * Click 'Search Now'
  * Double click on the folders that are found
  * 'Select' any cookie file
  * Use the 'Delete' button on your keyboard

If you are not using Microsoft Windows Explorer, then you should select 'cookies' in the 'Help' function for information on where to find your cookie folder. We do not pass on, or sell cookies to any other companies. Further information on the use of and managing cookies can be found at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
